Guide to the Robert Nathan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robert Nathan papers
1796-1985
1912-1968
YCAL MSS 307
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
45
(121 boxes)
The collection includes drafts of writings, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, clippings, drawings, diaries, and audio recordings documenting the life and work of the American writer Robert Nathan. Drafts of Nathan's writings make up the bulk of the collection, and include novels, screenplays, short fiction and prose, speeches, and poetry; the writings include story ideas, or "false starts," that Nathan did not publish. Correspondence and other papers document his family relationships, in particular that with his sister Marian Kraus Sandor. Other major correspondents include Stephen Vincent Benét, Herbert Feis, Lawrence Kubie, Dan H. Laurence, and Marjorie Bitker. The collection also documents an exhibition of Nathan's work in the Yale University Library in 1962.
Nathan, Robert, 1894-1985
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and Bequest of Robert G. Nathan, 1963-1990; Gift of Anna Lee Nathan, 1986; Gift of Marian Nathan Kraus Sandor, 1970; Gift of John W. Kraus, 2008. Gift of Marjorie M. Bitker, 1982-1985. Gift of Dan H. Laurence, 1966. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Feis, 1969-1971. Other gifts and purchases as indicated on individual folders.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 80 (audio reels): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Nathan, Robert (1894-1985)
The writer Robert Gruntal Nathan was born on January 2, 1894, in New York City to Harold Nathan, a prominent lawyer, and Sara Gruntal Nathan. He graduated from Philips Exeter Academy in 1912, and attended Harvard, where he edited the The Harvard Monthly. He married in 1915 and left Harvard without a degree in order to support his family. He worked briefly in advertising, but soon became a successful and prolific writer of novels, plays, essays, and poetry. Many of his novels were adapted into films, including The Bishop's Wife (1928) and Portrait of Jennie (1940), and in the 1940s he worked directly as a screenwriter for M-G-M Studios in Hollywood. Nathan was active in the National Institute of Arts and Letters, PEN, and the Academy of American Poets, among other organizations.
After his first marriage to Dorothy Michaels ended in 1922, Nathan married six more times: to Nancy Wilson, 1930-1936; to Lucy Lee Hall Skelding, 1936-1939; to Janet Bingham, 1940; to Clara May Burns, 1951; to Shirley Keeland, 1955-1969; and to the actress Anna Lee, 1970 until his death. He had one child, Joan Nathan Bergstrom, from his first marriage.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes drafts of writings, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, clippings, drawings, diaries, and audio recordings documenting the life and work of the American writer Robert Nathan. Drafts of Nathan's writings make up the bulk of the collection, and include novels, screenplays, short fiction and prose, speeches, and poetry; the writings include story ideas, or "false starts," that Nathan did not publish. Correspondence and other papers document his family relationships, in particular that with his sister Marian Kraus Sandor. Other major correspondents include Stephen Vincent Benét, Herbert Feis, Lawrence Kubie, Dan H. Laurence, and Marjorie Bitker. The collection also documents an exhibition of Nathan's work in the Yale University Library in 1962.
Arrangement
Organized into 4 groupings: Acquisitions 1964-circa 1970, Acquisitions circa 1970-1982, November 1982 Acquisition, and Other Acquisitions.
Material within this collection has been organized roughly by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time, and reflecting previous arrangement and description by the library. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition or group of acquisitions overlaps with/or relates to material found in other groups. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in all groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section. Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Screenwriters -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiotapes; Audiovisual materials; Diaries; Drawings (visual works); Photographic prints; Scrapbooks; Authors; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Bitker, Marjorie; Feis, Herbert, 1893-1972; Kubie, Lawrence S. (Lawrence Schlesinger), 1896-1973; Laurence, Dan H.; Nathan, Robert, 1894-1985; Sandor, Marian Nathan Kraus
- Acquisitions 1964-circa 1970, 1912-1963, undated; 16.89; (42 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two groupings: Writings and Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  Formerly classed as ZA Nathan.
  - Writings
    - Autumn, 2 (Box 1)
    - "Bad Men Have No Songs" (Box 1)
    - The Bishop's Wife
      - Autograph manuscript, 1928 (Box 1)
      - Original typescript, 1928 (Box 1)
      - Carbon typescript (Box 2)
    - "The Black Bull of Hanbury" (Box 2)
    - "Bolívar" (Box 2)
    - "Bridgit"
      - Autograph manuscript of original screenplay, 1945 March 28; 2 (Box 2)
      - Autograph manuscript of original manuscript (Box 2)
      - Original scenario (Box 2)
      - Setting typescript (Box 2)
      - Galley proofs (Box 3)
      - Page proofs, 2 (Box 3)
    - But Gently Day, 3 (Box 3)
    - "The Color of Evening"
      - Original manuscript drafts and notes (Box 3)
      - Author typescript (Box 3)
      - Original typescript (Box 4)
      - Setting typescript (Box 4)
      - Page proofs (Box 4)
      - Plate proofs (Box 4)
      - Revisions, 3 (Box 4)
    - "The Devil with Love"
      - Original manuscript draft and notes (Box 5)
      - Author typescript, 2 (Box 5)
      - Setting typescript (Box 5)
      - Page proofs, 2 (Box 5)
      - Plate proofs (Box 6)
      - Revisions, 2 (Box 6)
    - "Dunkirk" (Box 6)
    - "The Enchanted Voyage" (Box 6)
    - "England, My England" (Box 6)
    - "Ethiopia" (Box 6)
    - "Exeter" (Box 6)
    - "The Fair"
      - Original manuscript draft and notes (Box 6)
      - Author typescript (Box 6)
      - Setting typescript, 2 (Box 7)
      - Galley proof, 1963 November 1 (Box 7)
      - Page proof, 1963 November 29 (Box 7)
      - Plate proof (Box 7)
      - Revisions (Box 7)
    - "A Family Piece"
      - Manuscript and original typescript, 3 (Box 8)
      - Carbon typescript, 2 (Box 8)
      - Original typescript, 2 (Box 8)
    - "The Fiddler in Barly"
      - Manuscript and original typescript, 2 (Box 8)
      - Manuscript and original typescript (continued), 2 (Box 9)
        General note
        Includes comments by Robert Nathan's mother
      - Original typescript (Box 9)
    - "The Forsyte Saga", 4 (Box 9)
    - The Green Leaf (Box 9)
    - "The Heart in Wonder Like a Lonely Wren" (Box 10)
    - "Here in This Spot with You" (Box 10)
    - "A Hollywood Lad" (Box 10)
    - "The Ice Maiden", 2 (Box 10)
    - The Innocent Eve
      - Manuscript and typescript, with notes, 3 (Box 10)
      - Original typescript (Box 10)
      - Galley proof (Box 10)
      - Page proof (Box 11)
    - "Invincible" (Box 11)
    - Jezebel's Husband, 7
      - Manuscript first draft, 4 (Box 11)
      - Original typescript, 4 (Box 12)
      - Mimeographed typescript, 2 (Box 12)
    - Jonah
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 12)
      - Original typescript, 2 (Box 12)
      - Notes from typescript (Box 12)
      - Poem from manuscript (Box 12)
    - "Journal for Josephine" (Box 13)
    - Journey of Tapiola
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 13)
      - Original typescript (Box 13)
      - Carbon typescript, 2 (Box 13)
    - Juliet in Mantua
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 13)
      - Original typescript, 2 (Box 13)
    - "Lillies for Mr. Zanuck", 2 (Box 13)
    - Long After Summer
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 13)
      - Author typescript (Box 13)
      - Original and carbon typescript (Box 14)
      - Carbon typescript (Box 14)
      - Page proofs, 2 (Box 14)
    - "The Love Apple"
      - Original typescript (Box 14)
      - Typescripts, 3 (Box 14)
      - Original and mimeographed typescript (Box 14)
    - "The Married Look" (Box 15)
    - "Mephisto"
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 15)
      - Original typescript, 4 (Box 15)
    - "Messer Marco Polo"
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 15)
      - Author typescript, 2 (Box 15)
      - Original typescript, 5 (Box 16)
      - Original and carbon typescript (Box 16)
      - Notes and poems from manuscript (Box 16)
    - "Mr. Whittle and the Morning Star" (Box 16)
    - Morning in Iowa
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 16)
      - Original and carbon typescripts, 2 (Box 17)
      - Setting typescript (Box 17)
      - Galley proofs (Box 17)
      - Page proofs (Box 17)
    - "Music at Evening"
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 17)
      - Author typescript (Box 17)
      - Original typescript, 2 (Box 17)
    - "A Note to the Younger Generation" (Box 17)
    - One More Spring
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 17)
      - Author typescript, 2 (Box 17)
      - Original typescript (Box 18)
      - Galley proofs, 2 (Box 18)
      - Page proofs (Box 18)
    - "The Orchid"
      - Manuscript and typescript (Box 18)
      - Original typescript (Box 18)
      - Setting typescript (Box 18)
    - Peter Kindred
      - Autograph manuscript, 7 (Box 19)
      - Autograph manuscript, 3 (Box 20)
      - Original typescript, 4 (Box 21)
      - Original typescript (carbon copy), 4 (Box 21)
      - Correspondence (Box 21)
    - Portrait of Jennie, 2 (Box 22)
    - "A Pride of Carrots"
      - Original manuscript (Box 22)
      - Author typescript (Box 22)
      - Original typescript (Box 22)
    - "The Puppet Master"
      - Original manuscript and typescript (Box 22)
      - Carbon typescript (Box 22)
      - Original manuscript (Box 22)
    - "The Rancho of Little Loves"
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 22)
      - Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 22)
      - Original typescript, 2 (Box 23)
      - Author typescript (Box 23)
      - Typescript notes (Box 23)
    - "Red Shoes Run Faster" (Box 23)
    - The River Journey
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 23)
      - Author typescript (Box 23)
      - Secretary's typescript (Box 23)
      - Setting typescript (Box 23)
      - Page proof (Box 24)
      - Plate proof (Box 24)
    - Road of Ages
      - Notes (Box 24)
      - First draft, manuscript and typescript, 2 (Box 24)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected (Box 24)
      - Original typescript (Box 25)
      - Setting typescript, 2 (Box 25)
      - Lecture, draft (Box 25)
      - Galley proof (Box 25)
    - "Rombadille"
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 25)
      - Original typescript, bound (Box 26)
    - The Sea-Gull Cry
      - Notes (Box 27)
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 27)
      - First typescript, corrected (Box 27)
      - Author's typescript (Box 27)
      - Setting typescript (Box 27)
    - Sir Henry
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 27)
      - Author typescript (Box 27)
      - Secretary's typescript (original) (Box 27)
      - Secretary's typescript (carbon) (Box 27)
      - Secretary's typescript (second) (Box 27)
      - Secretary's typescript (third) (Box 28)
      - Setting typescript (Box 28)
      - Page proofs, 2 (Box 28)
    - The Sleeping Beauty
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 28)
      - First typed draft (Box 28)
      - Second typed draft (Box 28)
      - Carbon typescript (Box 29)
      - Original typescript (Box 29)
    - The Snowflake and the Starfish
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 29)
      - Author first typescript (Box 29)
      - Author second typescript (Box 29)
    - So Love Returns
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 29)
      - Author first typescript (Box 29)
      - Author second typescript (Box 29)
      - Secretary's first typescript, 2 (Box 29)
    - "The Son of God" (Box 29)
    - "The Sorcerer", 3 (Box 29)
    - Star in the Wind
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 30)
      - Author typescript, 3 (Box 30)
      - Secretary's typescript, 3 (Box 30)
      - Setting typescript, 3 (Box 31)
      - Carbon typescript, 3 (Box 31)
      - Galley proof (Box 31)
      - Page proof, 2 (Box 32)
      - Plate proof (Box 32)
      - Notes (Box 32)
      - Second draft, corrected (Box 32)
      - Second draft, corrected (continued) (Box 33)
      - Author's notes and corrections, 4 (Box 33)
      - Scenario of original typescript (Box 33)
    - "Strangers from Heaven"
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 33)
      - Author first typescript (Box 33)
      - Author second typescript (Box 33)
      - Secretary's first typescript (Box 33)
      - Secretary's second typescript (Box 33)
    - "Sweet Peep"
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 34)
      - Carbon typescript (Box 34)
    - Tapiola's Brave Regiment
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 35)
      - Author first typescript (Box 35)
      - Author second typescript (Box 35)
      - Secretary's typescript (Box 35)
      - Setting typescript (Box 35)
      - Galley proof (Box 35)
      - Page proof (Box 35)
    - There Is Another Heaven (Box 35)
    - The Train in the Meadow
      - Autograph manuscript (Box 35)
      - Author typescript (Box 35)
      - Secretary's typescript (Box 35)
    - "When Pegasus" (Box 35)
    - "The White Cliffs of Dover" (Box 35)
    - Winter in April
      - Setting typescript (Box 36)
      - Galley proofs (Box 36)
    - A Winter Tide
      - Galley proof (Box 36)
      - Page proof (Box 36)
      - Plate proof (Box 36)
  - Correspondence
    - Benét, Steven Vincent (copies) (Box 37)
    - Feis, Herbert, 1916-1936; 8 (Box 37)
    - Gruntal, Mrs. Herman, 1912-1941; 2 (Box 38)
    - Hale, Richard (Box 38)
    - Kubie, Mr. and Mrs. Lawrence S., 1920-1931; 5 (Box 38)
    - Leighton, Constance, 1948 February 2 (Box 39)
    - Nathan, Dorothy
      - To Robert Nathan, 1913-1939; 5 (Box 39)
      - From Robert Nathan, 1916-1921; 3 (Box 39)
      - From Robert Nathan, 1916-1921; 4 (Box 40)
    - Nathan, Harold and Sara, 1912-1941; 2 (Box 40)
    - Nathan, Harold and Sara, 1912-1941; 3 (Box 41)
    - Nathan family correspondence (Box 41)
    - Norman, Ruth Alice, 1925 (Box 41)
    - Sandor, Marian Nathan Kraus (Box 41)
    - Wise, Stephen S. (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous letters to Robert Nathan, 4 (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous writings (Box 42)
- Acquisitions circa 1970-1982, 1910-1968; 14.6; (37 boxes)
  Formerly classed as Uncat Za Nathan.
  Organized into 4 groupings: Correspondence, Writings, Material from Other Sources, and Personal Material.
  - Correspondence
    - General correspondence, 1910-1958; 2 (Box 43)
    - Bingham, William J. (Box 43)
    - Clark, B. Preston, Jr. (bound volume), 1913-1919 (Box 44)
    - Frederick, John T. (Box 43)
    - Lehmann, Lotte, 1947-1950 (Box 43)
    - Rollins, Leighton, no year July 21 (Box 43)
    - Sargent, Lucias M. (Box 43)
  - Writings
    - "American Singing" (Box 45)
    - "Answer to Millay" (Box 45)
    - "Anything Is Possible", 1963-1964 (Box 45)
    - "Ask not for freedom if you fear to weep" (Box 45)
    - "Atque Vale" (Box 45)
    - Autobiography
      - Autograph manuscript and notes for section 1894-1935, 3 (Box 45)
      - Typescript, corrected, 2 (Box 45)
      - Replaced pages (Box 45)
    - "Ave Imperator" (Box 45)
    - "The Bird Cage", 1918 (Box 45)
    - "Cape Cod", 1963 (Box 45)
    - "A Christmas Carol" (Box 46)
    - "His Daughter Clementine", 3 (Box 46)
    - "The Devil With Love" (Box 46)
    - "Digging the Weans", 2 (Box 46)
    - "Dr. Murphy"
      - Draft with revisions, 4 (Box 47)
      - Later revisions (Box 47)
      - Critiques, 2 (Box 47)
      - Cuts from Chapter 22 and 23 (Box 47)
      - Notes, 2 (Box 47)
      - Notes (continued), 2 (Box 48)
      - Photocopied draft, 2 (Box 48)
      - Sense of story (Box 48)
      - Synopsis and prologue (Box 48)
      - Synopsis, letters to Robert Kirsch (Box 48)
    - "The Earth Man" (Box 48)
    - "The Elixir"
      - Setting copy (original) (Box 48)
      - Page proofs (Box 48)
    - "For a Child, With a Christmas Tree" (Box 48)
    - "Foreword" (Box 48)
    - "The Gentleman" (Box 48)
    - "God Without A Name" (Box 48)
    - "The High Hat" (Box 49)
    - "Il Passa" (Box 49)
    - "The Influence of It" (Box 49)
    - Juliet in Mantua
      - Carbon typescript with corrections, 6 (Box 49)
      - Corrections during rehearsal, 2 (Box 49)
      - Autograph and typed corrections before rehearsal, 3 (Box 50)
      - Typescript corrections before rehearsal, 2 (Box 50)
      - Typescript and manuscript changes (Box 50)
      - Typescript corrections after second stencil, 2 (Box 50)
      - Setting copy (Box 50)
      - Television script changed to play (Box 51)
      - Working copy (Box 51)
      - Galley proofs (Box 51)
      - Page proofs, 2 (Box 51)
    - "A Letter to Nyere" (Box 52)
    - "Lillies for Mr. Zanuck" (Box 52)
    - "The Making of Me" (Box 52)
    - "The Mallot Diaries"
      - Autograph manuscript, 2 (Box 52)
      - Author typescript (Box 52)
      - Carbon typescript (Box 52)
      - Typescript with corrections (Box 52)
      - Corrections, criticism (Box 53)
      - Notes (Box 53)
      - Galley proofs (Box 53)
      - Page proofs (Box 53)
      - Final proofs, 2 (Box 53)
    - "Mamie, a Melodrama" (Box 53)
    - "The Married Look"
      - "Author's holograph, first typings, corrections, and revisions" (Box 54)
      - Notes (Box 54)
    - "The Married Man"
      - Typescript, 3 (Box 54)
      - Setting typescript (Knopf copy) (Box 54)
      - Drawings (Knopf copy), 2 (Box 54)
      - Light verse, 2 (Box 54)
      - Page proofs (Knopf copy), 1962; 2 (Box 55)
    - "Messr Marco Polo" (Box 55)
    - "Mr. Hudson" (Box 55)
    - "My True Love's Virtues" (Box 55)
    - "On Growing Old" (Box 55)
    - "On the State of Mankind" (Box 55)
    - "The Plight of a Writer..." (Box 55)
    - "Prayer in an Evil Time" (Box 55)
    - "Prosperine" (Box 55)
    - "Retort to the Nathan" by Josephine (Box 55)
    - Review of Frank Case work (Box 55)
    - So Love Returns
      - Original script (Box 55)
      - Motion picture script; typescript with revisions (Box 55)
      - Motion picture script; typescript with revisions (continued) (Box 56)
      - Revised script with notes, 2 (Box 56)
      - Revised script with notes (version 2), 2 (Box 56)
      - Revised script with notes (version 3), 2 (Box 56)
    - "The Society of Saving Fallen Girls" (Box 56)
    - "The Son of God" (Box 56)
    - "Sonnet to Man" (Box 56)
    - "sQgee of the Fly Pack" (Box 56)
    - Stonecliff
      - Autograph manuscript with notes (Box 57)
      - Autograph manuscript with notes (continued) (Box 57)
      - Revised draft with notes (Box 57)
      - Author typescript, 2 (Box 57)
      - Secretary's typescript (Box 57)
      - Agent's copy (Box 57)
      - Setting copy, 2 (Box 57)
      - Page proofs, 2 (Box 58)
      - Page proofs and galleys, 2 (Box 58)
      - Plate proofs (Box 58)
    - "Third Man High" (Box 58)
    - "Tina Nina", 1930 (Box 58)
    - "To Come with Me" (Box 58)
    - "Torpedo 8" (Box 58)
    - "Tyrannosaurus Rex", 2 (Box 58)
    - "Why Abraham?" (Box 58)
    - "The Whole Duty to a Pipe" (Box 59)
    - "The Wilderness Stone"
      - Autograph manuscript, 1960; 2 (Box 59)
      - Author typescript, 2 (Box 59)
      - Setting typescript, 2 (Box 59)
      - False start (Box 59)
      - Changes from first draft (Box 59)
      - Notes, 2 (Box 59)
      - Page proofs, 1960 November; 2 (Box 60)
    - A Winter Tide (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous writings (Box 60)
    - Early writings (Box 60)
    - Pages of earliest manuscript, 3 (Box 60)
    - Pages of earliest manuscript (continued), 3 (Box 61)
    - False starts, 1936-1964; 7 (Box 61)
    - False starts (continued), 1936-1964; 4 (Box 62)
    - Light verse, 1959 (Box 62)
    - Verse, small pieces (Box 62)
    - Untitled novel, 2 (Box 62)
    - Untitled play, 1933 (Box 62)
    - Untitled play, written with George S. Kaufman (Box 62)
    - Short pieces, 1918-1958, undated; 19 (Box 63)
    - Short pieces (continued), 1918-1958, undated; 6 (Box 64)
    - Movie originals (Box 65)
    - Notes, 1941-1957, undated; 10 (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 (Box 65)
  - Material from other sources
    - Benét, Steven Vincent. Correspondence, 1925-1943 (Box 66)
    - Feis, Herbert. Juliet in Mantua, mimeographed typescript prepared for television, Undated (Box 66)
    - Laurence, Dan H.
      Biographical/Historical note
      Compiler of Robert Nathan, a bibliography (Yale University Library, 1960).
      - Correspondence, 1913-1965; 5 (Box 66)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1913-1965; 10 (Box 67)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1913-1965; 2 (Box 68)
      - Writings
        - "Bridgit" (Box 68)
        - "The Color of Evening", 1960 (Box 68)
        - "The Devil with Love", 1963 (Box 68)
        - "Digging the Weans", 1959-1960; 5 (Box 68)
        - Juliet in Mantua (Box 69)
        - "The Married Man" (Box 69)
        - Music for "Il Passa" and So Love Returns (Box 69)
        - Portrait of Jennie (Box 69)
        - A Star in the Wind (Box 69)
        - Author sheets (Box 69)
        - Bibliographic material, 3 (Box 69)
        - Bibliographic material (continued), 2 (Box 70)
        - Robert Nathan writings, 2 (Box 70)
        - Photographs (Box 70)
        - Photostats (Box 70)
        - Printed material (Box 70)
    - Pettee, Charles E. One More Spring, fragments of holograph and typescript drafts numbered 107a and 114, undated (Box 70)
    - Sandor, Marian Nathan Kraus
      - Correspondence, 1920-1968; 20 (Box 71)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 9 (Box 72)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 5 (Box 73)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 5 (Box 74)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 5 (Box 75)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 6 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 6 (Box 77)
      - Correspondence (continued), 1920-1968; 6 (Box 78)
  - Personal material
    - Childhood drawings (Box 79)
    - Framed drawing by RN; framed print (?) of drawing of Robert Nathan, 2 (Box 79)
    - Photographs, 4 (Box 79)
    - Printed ephemera, 2 (Box 79)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 79)
    - Audiotape reels, (4 reels)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      Includes readings from Morning in Iowa, sonnets, poetry, light lyrics, etc.
      - Robert Nathan, "Sonnets, Light Lyrics", undated; 1; 00:29:22; There is static and high background noise on the tape. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002091248592)
      - [Nathan] Poetry, "War Poems: [Early] Lyrics, Sonnets", undated; 1; 00:30:14; There is high background noise on the tape. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002091248600)
      - "Morning in Iowa", Part I, Tape #2, undated; 1; 00:30:26; There is high background noise on the tape. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002091248618)
      - "Morning in Iowa", Part 2, Tape #3, undated; 1; 00:30:38; There is high background noise on the tape. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002091248626)
- November 1982 Acquisition, 1925-1982, undated; 5.42; (16 boxes)
  Arranged into two groupings: Correspondence and Writings.
  Formerly classed as Uncat Za MS 344
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous correspondence A-Z, 1964-1982; 16 (Box 81)
    - Beagle, Peter, 1966-1982; 5 (Box 82)
    - Kubie, Lawrence, 1961-1980; 3 (Box 82)
    - Wolmut, Felice, 1973-1982; 9 (Box 83)
    - Worley, Lin, 1979-1980; 2 (Box 83)
    - Young, Robert, 1979-1982; 3 (Box 84)